# 哈喽大家好
Hello everyone
# 我是王刚
I’m Wang Gang
# 前段时间我和粉丝们
Recently I introduced to my fans
# 分享了这款大的菜板
This big chopping board
# 粉丝们都说这个不适合家庭用
Many of you said that it’s not suitable for family use
# 分享了等于白说
Which my sharing was wasted
# 现在我跟大家分享一下这一款
So now I am gonna introduce to you guys about this one
# 就是两个材质都差不多
The texture of them both are similar
# 这个是松木的
This is made of pine wood
# 这个是银杏木的
This one is made of gingko wood
# 都是属于软木类的
They are both in the cork wood category
# 然后这个菜板更小
And this chopping board is much smaller
# 更适合家用
More suitable for family’s to own
# 这个的话其实也佷好用
This one is very good to use as well
# 但是就是重量大 体积大
But it’s much heavier and larger
# 容易发霉不好保养
Earlier to go moldy and harder to maintain
# 然后这个木头的话
And this wood
# 剁久了也会掉木渣
If you use for a while, there will be wood bits fallen off too
# 我之前也用过铁木
I’ve used ironwood
# 这个菜板的话
This chopping board
# 它有一个最不好的缺点就是
The one flaw it has is
# 切菜的时候
When you’re chopping
# 这样切的时候特别光滑特别硬
It’s very smooth and hard
# 很费刀
Which would worn off the knife easily
# 费刀
quite possibly to wear off
# 四伯爷也是懂行的
Uncle knows
# 肯定的 硬的肯定费刀
For sure, the hard ones definitely would wear off knives
# 我伯爷都这样说的
My uncle said so too
# 你切肉都是喜欢用软的是吗
Do you prefer softer boards for chopping meat?
# 肯定的 软的没有那么费刀
Certainly softer ones doesn’t wear off knives like that
# 铁木比较硬
Ironwood is way harder
# 剁东西伤刀
Chopping would damage the knives
# 第一伤刀 第二特别危险
First it would damage the knives, secondly it’s a lot more dangerous
# 松木和银杏木最大的优点
The best part of pinewood and gingko wood is
# 就是不费刀 不损刀
They don’t wear off and damage knives
# 也适合剁 不会掉很多（木屑）
More suitable for chopping and doesn’t have a lot of wood bits fallen
# 会掉一点点
Just a little bit
# 你剁上去像这样有一个孔
When you chop on it, there will be hole left on it
# 你稍微沾一点水
When you put on a bit of water
# 它就又长回去了
It grows right back
# 这是它最大的一个优点
That’s the best part of it
# 再一个是轻巧
And it’s light as well
# 还有一个就是它是现切下来的
Also it’s freshly sawed off
# 因为这个皮都还在
Because the skin is still left on it
# 我们还有一些粉丝说
Some of our fans also mentioned
# 家里面用的竹子拼接起来的（菜板）
Chopping boards homemade by bamboo
# 它是用胶水粘起来的
It’s stocked together by glue
# 用胶水粘起来的话
When it’s glued together
# 切东西会掉木屑
There will be wood bits fallen out as well
# 本来它就是胶做的
Because it’s been glued together
# 本来就是胶的呀
It’s glued together anyways
# 那不是怎么的
So what about it
# 不是 它是竹子
No it’s made of bamboo
No it’s bamboo
# 竹胶板来粘的
Glued together bamboo board
# 对对对
Yeah right
# 用胶粘的
Glued together
# 那个不好
That not good
# 只有这个菜板更好
Only this chopping board is better
# 这个菜板唯一有一点不好
The one bad thing about this board is
# 你要经常用
You have to use it constantly
# 不经常用的话容易发霉 也会裂
Otherwise it would get moldy and have cracks
# 但是这个裂的话有办法可以恢复
But if it had cracks, there’s a way to fix it
# 裂了之后就是泡盐水
After you have cracks, soak it in salted water
# 泡完盐水之后
After it has been soaked by salted water
# 这样子把这个水推干之后
wipe off the water like this
# 抹点油就没有问题
put on some oil and it will be all good
# 这个比这个更容易发霉 还重
This one is much easier to get mold than that one
# 这个菜板适合小家庭用
This chopping board is perfect for family use
# 这菜板就是这两年我选来选去
This chopping board is which I have picked out in this couple years
# 还是觉得这款更适合大家使用
This kind is the best for you guys to use
# 因为这个是现切现做
Because it’s for chopping and cooking right away
# 这个菜板又不占地方
the board doesn’t take up much space
# 随拿随走
You can just grab and go
# 一只手都可以拿起来
Lifting by only one hand
# 这个大概有七八斤
This one is 3 to 4 kilograms
# 看厚度我这款是五公分
And the thickness is about 5 centimeters
# 这还有个小缺点
And another little thing is that
# 就是比这个贵
It’s a little more expensive than that
# 你可以看到这两个
You can see those two
# 同样的砧板价格是差不了多少
Similar chopping boards have similar prices
# 这个也是一百多
This is about a hundred
That’s about a hundred as well
# 但是你说哪个更好用的话
But if you wonder which is better
# 家庭我就推荐你用这个
Family use I would recommend this one
# 单位里面或者是商用那绝对是这个
But if for restaurants or business use than definitely this one
# 还是那句话这个保养就两条
And again there are two keys of maintaining
# 泡盐水 泡完盐水之后刮掉
Soak with salted water and wipe off after
# 把水去掉 抹油
Wipe off and put on some oil
# 基本上都可以这样来保养
You can just basically maintain like that
# 好了 本期视频就给你们种下草
Alright Today’s video is basically introducing the products
# 好不好
Alright?
# 推荐你们用下这个
Really recommend you guys to try this out
# 好了 就到这里
Ok that’s it for today
# 拜拜
Bye~